Hi there.
أهلا بكم
I'm going to be talking a little bit about
سأتحدث قليلا عن
music, machines and life.
الموسيقى، الآلات والحياة
Or, more specifically,
أو، بالأخص
what we learned from the creation of a very large and complicated machine
ما تعلمناه من صناعة آلة ضخمة ومعقدة جدا
for a music video.
لفيديو موسيقي
Some of you may recognize this image.
بعضكم قد يتعرف على هذه الصورة
This is the opening frame of the video that we created.
هذه اللقطة الإفتتاحية من الفيديو الذي صنعناه
We'll be showing the video at the end,
سنعرض المقطع في النهاية
but before we do, I want to talk a little bit about
ولكن قبل أن نفعل ذلك، أود التحدث قليلا عن
what it is that they wanted.
ما أرادوه
Now, when we first started talking to OK Go --
الآن، حين بدأنا التحدث مع "أوك جو"
the name of the song is "This Too Shall Pass" --
إسم الأغنية "هذا أيضا سيمضي"
we were really excited because
كنا متحمسين جدا لأنهم
they expressed interest in building a machine that they could dance with.
أبدو إهتمامهم بصنع آلة يمكنهم الرقص معها
And we were very excited about this
وكنا متحمسين جدا لذلك
because, of course,
لأنهم، بالطبع
they have a history of dancing with machines.
لهم تاريخ في الرقص مع الآلات
They're responsible for this video, "Here It Goes Again."
إنهم المسؤولين عن هذا المقطع، "ها نحن نعيد الكرة"
50-million-plus views on YouTube.
أكثر من 50 مليون مشاهد على يوتيوب
Four guys dancing on treadmills,
أربع أشخاص يرقصون على آلالات المشي
no cuts, just a static camera.
بدون تقطيع، فقط كاميرا ثابتة
A fantastically viral and wonderful video.
مقطع رائع حقق إنتشارا كبيرا
So we were really excited about working with them.
فكنا متحمسين جدا للعمل معهم
And we sort of started talking about what it is that they wanted.
وبدأنا التحدث عن مرادهم
And they explained that they wanted
وشرحوا أنهم يريدون
kind of a Rube Goldberg machine.
نوع من آلات روبي جولدبيرت
Now, for those of you who don't know,
لمن لا يعرف منكم
a Rube Goldberg machine
آلة روبي جولدبيرت
is a complicated contraption,
هي آلة غريبة الشكل
an incredibly over-engineered piece of machinery
مهندسة بشكل معقد ومبالغ به
that accomplishes a relatively simple task.
لتؤدي عملا بسيط نسبيا
So we were excited by this idea,
وقد تحمسنا لهذه الفكرة
and we started talking about
وبدأنا بالحديث عن
exactly what it would look like.
شكلها النهائي
And we came up with some parameters, because,
وتوصلنا إلى بعض المواصفات
you know, building a Rube Goldberg machine
فبناء آلة روبي جولدبيرت
has limitations,
له حدوده
but it also is pretty wide open.
وكما أنه مفتوح على مصراعيه
And we wanted to make sure that we did something
وأردنا التأكد بأننا سنصنع شيئا
that would work for a music video.
يتماشى مع المقطع
So we came up with a list of requirements,
فتوصلنا إلى قائمة الإحتياجات
the "10 commandments,"
الوصايا العشر
and they were, in order of ascending difficulty:
وهي مذكورة من الأسهل إلى الأصعب
The first is "No magic."
الأول "لا سحر"ـ
Everything that happened on screen had to be
كل ما يحدث على الشاشة يجب أن يكون
very easily understood by a typical viewer.
سهل جدا للفهم من قبل المشاهد العادي
The rule of thumb was that, if my mother couldn't understand it,
القاعدة هي، لو لم تفهمهم أمي
then we couldn't use it in the video.
إذا لا يمكننا إستخدامه في المقطع
They wanted band integration,
أرادو دمج الفرقة
that is, the machine acting upon the band members,
وذلك بأن تتصرف الآلة بأعضاء الفرقة
specifically not the other way around.
تحديدا وليس بالعكس
They wanted the machine action to follow the song feeling.
أرادو أن تتوافق حركات الآلة مع شعور الأغنية
So as the song picks up emotion,
فكلما تحولت الأغنية إلى شعور
so should the machine
كذلك يجب أن تتحول الآلة
get grander in its process.
إلى حركات أكبر
They wanted us to make use of the space.
أرادو أن نستغل المساحة
So we have this 10,000-square-foot warehouse we were using,
فلدينا مستودع 10,000 قدم مربع
divided between two floors.
مقسومة بين طابقين
It included an exterior loading dock.
ولديها منصة خارجية للتحميل
We used all of that, including a giant hole in the floor
إستخدمنا كل المساحة، بما في ذلك حفرة في الأرض
that we actually descended the camera and cameraman through.
إنزلنا فيها الكاميرا وطاقم التصوير
They wanted it messy, and we were happy to oblige.
أرادو أن تكون فوضوية، ووافقنا بفرحة
The machine itself would start the music.
على الآلة نفسها أن تبدأ الموسيقى
So the machine would get started,
فالآلة تبدأ
it would travel some distance,
وتعمل لبعض الوقت
reacting along the way,
متفاعلة
hit play on an iPod or a tape deck
تضغط زر البدأ
or something that would start playback.
أو شيء ما ليبدأ العرض
And the machine would maintain synchronization throughout.
على الآلة أن تحافظ على توافقها طوال الوقت
And speaking of synchronization,
على ذكر التوافق
they wanted it to sync to the rhythm
أرادو أن تتوافق مع اللحن
and to hit specific beats along the way.
وأن تضرب على نغمات معينة
Okay. (Laughter)
حسنا (ضحك)
They wanted it to end precisely on time.
أرادوا أن تنتهي عند الوقت تماما
Okay, so now the start to finish timing has to be perfect.
حسنا، فالآن والتوقيت من البداية حتى النهاية يجب أن تكون دقيقة
And they wanted the music to drop out
وأرادو الموسيقى أن تختفي
at a certain point in the video
في نقطة معينة من المقطع
and actual live audio from the machine
وتلعب أصوات حية من الآلة
to play part of the song.
أجزاءا من الأغنية
And as if that wasn't enough,
وكأن ذلك لم يكن كافيا
all of these incredibly complicating things, right,
كل هذه الأمور الرائعة المعقدة
they wanted it in one shot.
أرادو أن تصور في لقطة واحدة
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Okay.
حسنا
So, just some statistics
بعض من الإحصائيات
about what we went through in the process.
عن، تقريبا، ما مررنا به في العملية
The machine itself has
الآلة ذاتها لديها
89 distinct interactions.
89 تفاعل مستقل
It took us 85 takes
إحتجنا إلى 85 تجربة
to get it on film
لتصويرها
to our satisfaction.
كما يرضينا
Of those 85 takes,
من هذه الـ 85
only three actually successfully completed their run.
فقط 3 أتممت التشغيل بنجاح
We destroyed two pianos
دمرنا آلتي بيانو
and 10 televisions in the process.
و 10 تلفزيونات خلال العملية
We went to Home Depot well over a hundred times.
ذهبنا إلى هووم ديبو أكثر من مائة مرة
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And we lost one high-heeled shoe
وفقدنا جزمة كعب عالي
when one of our engineers, Heather Knight,
حين تركت أحد المهندسات
left her high-heeled shoe -- after a nice dinner,
جزمتها ذات الكعب العالي -- بعد عشاء ممتع
and returned back to the build --
وعادت إلى البناء
and left it in a pile of stuff.
وتركتها في كومة من الأشياء
And another engineer thought, "Well, that would be a really good thing to use"
وإعتقد مهندس آخر "هذا شيء جيد يمكن إستخدامه"ـ
and ended up using it as a really nice trigger.
وإنتهى به الأمر بإستخدامه كمشغل جيد
And it's actually in the machine.
وهي في الآلة الآن
So what did we learn from all of this?
فماذا تعلمنا من كل ذلك؟
Well, having completed this,
بعد إنهاء هذا الأمر
we have the opportunity to step back and reflect
لدينا فرصة التوقف والتأمل
on some of the things.
في بعض الأمور
And we learned that small stuff stinks.
وتعلمنا أن الأمور الصغيرة نتنة
Little balls in wooden tracks
كرات صغيرة في ممرات خشبية
are really susceptible to
تتأثر جدا
humidity and temperature and a little bit of dust,
بالرطوبة والحرارة والقليل من الغبار
and they fall out of the tracks,
ويسقطون من الممر
the exact angles makes it hard to get right.
يصعب ضبط الزوايا
And yet, a bowling ball will always follow the same path.
وبالمقابل، فكرة البولنج ستتبع نفس الطريق دوما
It doesn't matter what temperature it is,
لا يهم درجة الحرارة
doesn't matter what's in its way;
ولا يهم ما يعيق طريقها
it will pretty much get where it needs to go.
ستصل تقريبا إلى حيث تحتاج
But as much as the small stuff stinks, we needed somewhere to start,
ولكن على قدر ما نكره الأمور الصغيرة، نحتاج لنقطة بداية
so that we would have somewhere to go.
لتكون لنا وجهة
And so you have to start with it. You have to focus on it.
ولذلك عليك البدء بها. وعليك التركيز عليها
Small stuff stinks,
الأمور الصغيرة نتنة
but, of course, it's essential, right?
ولكنها بالطبع ضرورية
What else? Planning is incredibly important.
ماذا أيضا؟ التخطيط مهم جدا
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
You know, we spent a lot of time ideating
تعلمون، نحن نمضي وقتا طويلا في الأفكار
and even building some of these things.
وأيضا في بناء بعض هذه الأشياء
It's been said that, "No battle plan
وقد قيل "لا توجد خطة حربية
survives contact with the enemy."
تتجاوز لقاء العدو"ـ
I think our enemy was physics --
أعتقد أن عدونا كان الفيزياء
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
and she's a cruel mistress.
وهي عشيقة شريرة
Often, we had to pull things out as a result
كثيرا ما إضطررنا إلى إستبعاد بعض الأشياء
because of timing or aesthetics or whatever.
نتيجة للتوقيت أو المناظر أو سبب ما
And so while planning is important, so is flexibility.
فالتخطيط مهم، ولكن المرونة كذلك
These are all things that ended up
هذه كلها أشياء إنتهى بها المطاف
not making it into the final machine.
خارج الآلة النهائية
So also, put reliable stuff last,
وكذلك ضع الأمور المؤكدة في النهاية
the stuff that's going to run every time.
الأشياء التي ستعمل كل مرة
Again, small to large is relevant here.
الصغير إلى الكبير أمر نسبي هنا
The little Lego car in the beginning of the video
سيارة الليجو الصغيرة في بداية المقطع
references the big, real car
في مقابل السيارة الكبيرة الحقيقية
near the end of the video.
قرب نهاية المقطع
The big, real car works every time; there's no problem about it.
السيارة الكبيرة الحقيقية تعمل كل مرة، لا توجد بها أي مشاكل
The little one had a tendency to try to run off the track
الصغيرة كانت عادة ما تحاول لخروج عن الطريق
and that's a problem.
وتلك مشكلة
But you don't want to have to reset the whole machine
ولا ترغب في أن تضطر لمعاودة الكرة على الآلة كاملة
because the Lego car at the end doesn't work, right.
لأن سيارة الليجو في النهاية لا تعمل
So you put that up front so that, if it fails,
فتضعها في البداية، حتى لو تعطلت
at least you know
على الأقل أنت تعلم
you don't have to reset the whole thing.
أنك لن تحتاج إلى إعادة الآلة كاملة
Life can be
يمكن للحياة أن تكون
messy.
فوضوية
There were incredibly difficult moments in the building of this thing.
كانت هناك لحظات صعبة جدا في بناء هذا الشيء
Months were spent in this tiny, cold warehouse.
أمضينا شهورا في هذا المستودع الصغير
And the wonderful elation that we had
والغبطة الرائعة التي شعرنا بها
when we finally completed it.
حين أنتهينا أخيرا
So it's important to remember that whether it's good or it's bad,
فعلينا التذكر بأن الأمور لو كانت جيدة أو سيئة
"This Too Shall Pass."
"هذه أيضا ستمضي"
Thank you very much.
شكرا جزيلا
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
And now to introduce
والآن ليقدموا
their music video,
مقطعهم الموسيقي
we have OK Go.
لدينا أوك جو
OK Go: An introduction. Hello TEDxUSC.
أوك جو: مقدمة. مرحبا تيد أكس يو إس سي
We are OK Go.
نحن أوك جو
What are we doing? Oh, just hanging out with our Grammy. What what!
ماذا نفعل؟ فقط نسترخي مع جائزتنا
It think we can do better than this. Hello TEDxUSC.
أعتقد أننا نستطيع أداء أفضل. مرحبا تيد أكس يو إس سي
We are OK Go. Have you read the "Natural Curiosity Cabinet?"
نحن أوك جو. هل قرأتم "دولاب الفضول الطبيعي؟"ـ
I mean, "Curiosity" -- excuse me.
أعني، الفضول -- عفوا
Let me start again.
دعني أبدأ من جديد
We need some more ridiculous things besides "The Cabinet of Natural Curiosities."
نحتاج إلى المزيد من الأومر السخيفة غير "دولاب الفضول الطبيعي"ـ
Tim's sundial hat.
قبعة تم الشمسية
Have you seen the new work they've done to the Waltz Towers?
هلا رأيتم الأعمال الجديدة التي أقيمت على برج والتز؟
Sorry, start again.
عذرا، إبدأ من جديد
(Barking)
(نباح)
Dogs.
كلاب
Hello, TEDxUSC. We are OK Go,
مرحبا تيد أكس يو إس سي نحن أوك جو
and this our new video, "This Too Shall Pass."
وهذا مقطعنا الجديد "هذا أيضا سيمضي"ـ
[unclear]
(غير واضح)
Kay, we can still do one better I think, yeah.
حسنا، أعتقد أننا لازلنا نستطيع تقديم واحد أفضل
That one's pretty good. It's getting better.
ذلك كان جيد جدا. أنها تتحسن
(Music)
(موسيقى)
♫ You know you can't keep letting it get you down ♫
♫ تعلم أنك لا يمكن أن تسمح لها أن تحبطك ♫
♫ And you can't keep dragging that dead weight around ♫
♫ ولا يمكنك سحب هذا الوزن الزائد في كل مكان ♫
♫ If there ain't all that much to lug around ♫
♫ لو لم يكن هناك الكثير للسحب ♫
♫ Better run like hell when you hit the ground ♫
♫ عليك الجري سريعا حين تصل إلى الأرض ♫
♫ When the morning comes ♫
♫ حين يأتي الصباح ♫
♫ You can't stop these kids from dancing ♫
♫ يمكنك منع هؤلاء الأطفال من الرقص ♫
♫ Why would you want to? ♫
♫ ولما سترغب بذلك ♫
♫ Especially when you're already getting yours ♫
♫ خصوصا وأنت تحصل على نصيبك ♫
♫ Cuz if your mind don't move and your knees don't bend ♫
♫ فإذا لم يتحرك عقلك ولم تنحني ركبك ♫
♫ Well don't go blaming the kids again ♫
♫ فلا تلون الأطفال مجددا ♫
♫ When the morning comes ♫
♫ حين يأتي الصباح ♫
♫ Let it go ♫
♫ دعها تذهب ♫
♫ This too shall pass ♫
♫ هذه أيضا ستمضي ♫
♫ You know you can't keep letting it get you down ♫
♫ تعلم أنك لا يمكن أن تسمح لها أن تحبطك ♫
♫ No, you can't keep letting it get you down ♫
♫ لا، لا يمكن أن تسمح لها باحباطك ♫
♫ Let it go ♫
♫ دعها تذهب ♫
♫ This too shall pass ♫
♫ هذه أيضا ستمضي ♫
♫ When the morning comes ♫
♫ حين يأتي الصباح ♫
(Cheering)
(هتاف)